

Sergei Shilko

Software Engineer



contact@sshilko.com

B http://sshilko.com

English, Russian, German, Polish, Ukrainian,











BACKGROUND

ABOUT

 $Hi, I\ am\ Sergei\ Shilko, i\ graduated\ in\ 2010\ MS\ Psychology\ with\ study\ on\ role\ of\ personal\ characteristics\ in\ a\ successful\ properties of\ personal\ characteristics\ in\ a\ successful\ properties\ propert$ Software/IT career. Since first year in university i already worked for IT company and now i have more than 10 years of experience in Web/IT engineering. I managed work on multiple software projects ranging from small plugins and internal IT systems to build from scratch backend systems for high load. My expertise domains are Web, Mobile and APIs for backend applications. I like to solve technical and business problems with focus on client requirements and working closely with product teams.

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Head of Engineering, Tripod Technlogy GmbH

SRE & Cloud Architecture of backend APIs, IT, Operations, Concept. Reporting and liaising directly with CEO & external

- Scaling and developing whole backend infrastructure
- Migrating whole stack into containers (Docker) and K8S
- · Costs optimized technology stack
- Promoting AWS Best Practices and Agile
- · China and SEA connectivity improvements and research

Senior FullStack Software Developer, Tripod Technlogy GmbH

Jun, 2013 - Jun, 2016 3 years

Mature backend solutions for audio/video (tele)communications software. Developing public API for mobile clients.

- Implemented first API for first version of mobile app
- Revamp of old codebase (prototype) into working product
- Deprecate legacy on-premise hosting and migration into AWS
- Defining the whole mobile optimized API's from ground-up for iOS and then Android clients
- 2015 Most innovative app of the year (Apple iTunes)

Lead Software Developer, Yangutu LLC

Nov, 2011 - Nov, 2012 🐧 1 ye

Working on web based social network.

- · Game platform add-on for product
- · AMF Flex/ActionScript API Server
- Facebook, Instagram and other social networks integration
- · Import/Export API's

Contractor, Cygno Solutions LLC

Sep, 2011 - Nov, 2011 O 2 months

Short term freelance experience, integrating payment gateways and external API into existing project

- PayPal integration
- DineroMail (SA Payment platform) integration

PHP Developer, eHarmony, Inc

Aug, 2008 - Sep, 2011 3 years 1 month

eHarmony Reporting and Management Tools for Risk Management team

- · CMS/RMS Internal website to manage and automate risks and fraud detection
- · Working with sensitive client abd payment information

Software Developer, IponWeb

Aug. 2007 - Sep. 2011 @ 4 years 1 month

SOAP/Rest API for real-time AD Exchange platform (formerly RightMedia.com)

- Working on API for real-time advertising platform at scale
- Implementing funtional test coverage for whole functionality and refactoring old tests

May, 2008 - Mar, 2009 🐧 10 months

Maintaining RightMedia AD Exchange API migration after Yahoo! purchase

· Refactoring tests, code and documentation, working with remote Yahoo developers team

Intern. Developer, Sinvtech LLC

Dec, 2005 - Aug, 2007 O 1 year 8 months

E-commerce websites for multiple clients/brands

- Learn Web and IT
- Learn CMS and development tools
- Integrate VeriSign payment processor
- Support custom CMS codebase (MVC)

